let questions = [{"numb": 1, "question": "sichern", "answer": "to ensure", "options": ["to make trip", "to measure", "to harm, to injure", "to ensure"]}, {"numb": 2, "question": "abpacken", "answer": "to pack something", "options": ["to critisize", "to burst, to blast", "to pack something", "to ensure"]}, {"numb": 3, "question": "leiden", "answer": "to suffer", "options": ["to suffer", "to voice, \u0ca7\u0ccd\u0cb5\u0ca8\u0cbf \u0c8e\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0ca4\u0cc1", "to explore", "to exist"]}, {"numb": 4, "question": "einwerfen", "answer": "to insert", "options": ["to drop in", "to invent", "to correspond", "to insert"]}, {"numb": 5, "question": "verzichten", "answer": "to quit", "options": ["to keep, to hold", "to quit", "to mention", "to find, discover"]}, {"numb": 6, "question": "beschr\u00e4nken_sich", "answer": "to restrict", "options": ["to look at", "to restrict", "to spread, \u0cb9\u0cb0\u0ca1u", "to follow"]}, {"numb": 7, "question": "verpassen", "answer": "to miss something \u0ca4\u0caa\u0ccd\u0caa\u0cc1\u0cb5\u0cbf\u0c95\u0cc6", "options": ["to miss something \u0ca4\u0caa\u0ccd\u0caa\u0cc1\u0cb5\u0cbf\u0c95\u0cc6", "to bear, to abide", "to relax", "to close, to shut"]}, {"numb": 8, "question": "nerven", "answer": "to get nervous", "options": ["to extend", "to sound", "to feed", "to get nervous"]}, {"numb": 9, "question": "werfen", "answer": "to through", "options": ["to exhibit, to show", "to make trip", "to through", "to drop in"]}, {"numb": 10, "question": "verlassen", "answer": "to leave", "options": ["to drop in", "to affect, \u0caa\u0cb0\u0cbf\u0ca3\u0cbe\u0cae\u0cb5\u0cbe\u0c97\u0cc1", "to leave", "to defend"]}, {"numb": 11, "question": "verkaufen", "answer": "to sell", "options": ["to explore", "to sell", "to voice, \u0ca7\u0ccd\u0cb5\u0ca8\u0cbf \u0c8e\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0ca4\u0cc1", "to prefer"]}, {"numb": 12, "question": "umgehen", "answer": "to byepass", "options": ["encourage, \u0caa\u0ccd\u0cb0\u0cc6\u0cc2\u0cd5\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0cb8\u0cbe\u0cb9\u0cbf\u0cb8", "to look at", "to critisize", "to byepass"]}, {"numb": 13, "question": "erm\u00fctigen", "answer": "encourage, \u0caa\u0ccd\u0cb0\u0cc6\u0cc2\u0cd5\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0cb8\u0cbe\u0cb9\u0cbf\u0cb8", "options": ["encourage, \u0caa\u0ccd\u0cb0\u0cc6\u0cc2\u0cd5\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0cb8\u0cbe\u0cb9\u0cbf\u0cb8", "to confirm, to approve", "to decide", "to suffer"]}, {"numb": 14, "question": "vorfinden", "answer": "to find, discover", "options": ["to insert", "to find, discover", "to recommond", "to make trip"]}, {"numb": 15, "question": "reinschauen", "answer": "to drop in", "options": ["to drop in", "to swap", "to keep, to hold", "to occur, \u0c95\u0cbe\u0ca3\u0cbf\u0cb8\u0cbf\u0c95\u0ccaLLu"]}, {"numb": 16, "question": "mitverfolgen", "answer": "to follow", "options": ["to follow", "to measure", "to stick", "to ensure"]}, {"numb": 17, "question": "gewehren_sich", "answer": "to defend", "options": ["to defend", "to pack something", "to prepare", "to find, discover"]}, {"numb": 18, "question": "freuen_sich", "answer": "to be glad", "options": ["to receive", "to be glad", "to shift", "to spend time"]}, {"numb": 19, "question": "erklingen", "answer": "to sound", "options": ["to be located", "to suffer", "to sound", "to keep, to hold"]}, {"numb": 20, "question": "aberglauben", "answer": "superstitious, andhavishwasa", "options": ["superstitious, andhavishwasa", "to affect, \u0caa\u0cb0\u0cbf\u0ca3\u0cbe\u0cae\u0cb5\u0cbe\u0c97\u0cc1", "to reqest, to apply for", "to make contact"]}, {"numb": 21, "question": "anbieten", "answer": "to offer", "options": ["to change dress", "to offer", "to suffer", "to through"]}, {"numb": 22, "question": "kontakte_kn\u00fcpfen", "answer": "to make contact", "options": ["to audition", "superstitious, andhavishwasa", "to recommond", "to make contact"]}, {"numb": 23, "question": "drauflegen", "answer": "to put on it", "options": ["to bear, to abide", "to put on it", "to watch", "to recommond"]}, {"numb": 24, "question": "erm\u00f6glichen", "answer": "to enable, \u0cb8\u0c95\u0ccd\u0cb0\u0cbf\u0caf\u0c97\u0cc6\u0cc2\u0cb3\u0cbf\u0cb8u, \u0c85\u0ca7\u0cbf\u0c95\u0cbe\u0cb0 \u0c95\u0cca\u0ca1\u0cc1", "options": ["to enable, \u0cb8\u0c95\u0ccd\u0cb0\u0cbf\u0caf\u0c97\u0cc6\u0cc2\u0cb3\u0cbf\u0cb8u, \u0c85\u0ca7\u0cbf\u0c95\u0cbe\u0cb0 \u0c95\u0cca\u0ca1\u0cc1", "to find, discover", "to occur, \u0c95\u0cbe\u0ca3\u0cbf\u0cb8\u0cbf\u0c95\u0ccaLLu", "to sell"]}, {"numb": 25, "question": "veranstallen", "answer": "to host, to arrange, event \u0c86\u0caf\u0cc6\u0cc2\u0cd5\u0c9c\u0cbf\u0cb8u", "options": ["to mark", "to host, to arrange, event \u0c86\u0caf\u0cc6\u0cc2\u0cd5\u0c9c\u0cbf\u0cb8u", "to keep, to hold", "to enter"]}, {"numb": 26, "question": "anziehen", "answer": "to change dress", "options": ["to bear, to abide", "to suit", "to mention", "to change dress"]}, {"numb": 27, "question": "beweisen", "answer": "to prove", "options": ["attract attention, to stand out", "to miss something \u0ca4\u0caa\u0ccd\u0caa\u0cc1\u0cb5\u0cbf\u0c95\u0cc6", "to ensure", "to prove"]}, {"numb": 28, "question": "einschalten", "answer": "to activate", "options": ["attract attention, to stand out", "to close, to shut", "to put on it", "to activate"]}, {"numb": 29, "question": "erholen", "answer": "to relax", "options": ["encourage, \u0caa\u0ccd\u0cb0\u0cc6\u0cc2\u0cd5\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0cb8\u0cbe\u0cb9\u0cbf\u0cb8", "to expire", "to relax", "to quit"]}, {"numb": 30, "question": "erweitern", "answer": "to extend", "options": ["to convience, \u0cae\u0ca8\u0cb5\u0cc6\u0cc2\u0cb2\u0cbf\u0cb8u, \u0cae\u0ca8\u0c97\u0cbe\u0ca3\u0cbf\u0cb8\u0cc1", "to insert", "to make contact", "to extend"]}, {"numb": 31, "question": "entsprechen", "answer": "to correspond", "options": ["to correspond", "to close, to shut", "to defend", "to restrain, \u0ca8\u0cbf\u0caf\u0c82\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0cb0\u0ca3 maadikoLLu"]}, {"numb": 32, "question": "erkunden", "answer": "to explore", "options": ["to change dress", "to spend time", "discourage, \u0ca8\u0cbf\u0cb0\u0cc1\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0cb8\u0cbe\u0cb9\u0c97\u0cca\u0cb3\u0cbfsu", "to explore"]}, {"numb": 33, "question": "verreisen", "answer": "to make trip", "options": ["to voice, \u0ca7\u0ccd\u0cb5\u0ca8\u0cbf \u0c8e\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0ca4\u0cc1", "to make trip", "to stick", "to activate"]}, {"numb": 34, "question": "empfangen", "answer": "to receive", "options": ["to receive", "to follow", "to invent", "to behave"]}, {"numb": 35, "question": "durchgehen", "answer": "to pass, to go through", "options": ["to prefer", "to pass, to go through", "to behave", "to spread, \u0cb9\u0cb0\u0ca1u"]}, {"numb": 36, "question": "ertragen", "answer": "to suffer, to endure", "options": ["to find, discover", "to receive", "to activate", "to suffer, to endure"]}, {"numb": 37, "question": "empfehlen", "answer": "to recommond", "options": ["to recommond", "to measure", "to be located", "to expire"]}, {"numb": 38, "question": "bevorzugen", "answer": "to prefer", "options": ["to byepass", "to quit", "to prefer", "to keep, to hold"]}, {"numb": 39, "question": "sprengen", "answer": "to burst, to blast", "options": ["to burst, to blast", "to relax", "to suffer", "to exist"]}, {"numb": 40, "question": "erhalten", "answer": "to receive", "options": ["to receive", "to voice, \u0ca7\u0ccd\u0cb5\u0ca8\u0cbf \u0c8e\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0ca4\u0cc1", "to leave", "to save data"]}, {"numb": 41, "question": "aushalten", "answer": "to bear, to abide", "options": ["to host, to arrange, event \u0c86\u0caf\u0cc6\u0cc2\u0cd5\u0c9c\u0cbf\u0cb8u", "to suit", "to bear, to abide", "to fill in"]}, {"numb": 42, "question": "markieren", "answer": "to mark", "options": ["to close, to shut", "to prefer", "to spread, \u0cb9\u0cb0\u0ca1u", "to mark"]}, {"numb": 43, "question": "vorspielen", "answer": "to audition", "options": ["to audition", "to host, to arrange, event \u0c86\u0caf\u0cc6\u0cc2\u0cd5\u0c9c\u0cbf\u0cb8u", "to pull", "to invent"]}, {"numb": 44, "question": "verraten", "answer": "to betray", "options": ["to quit", "to betray", "to exist", "to suit"]}, {"numb": 45, "question": "ausbilden", "answer": "to train", "options": ["to train", "to receive", "to fill up (bitta sthala tumbi)", "to connect"]}, {"numb": 46, "question": "vorbereiten_auf", "answer": "to prepare", "options": ["to have ones turn", "to prepare", "to get nervous", "to fill up (bitta sthala tumbi)"]}, {"numb": 47, "question": "wachen", "answer": "to watch", "options": ["to watch", "to make trip", "to keep up, to match up", "to enable, \u0cb8\u0c95\u0ccd\u0cb0\u0cbf\u0caf\u0c97\u0cc6\u0cc2\u0cb3\u0cbf\u0cb8u, \u0c85\u0ca7\u0cbf\u0c95\u0cbe\u0cb0 \u0c95\u0cca\u0ca1\u0cc1"]}, {"numb": 48, "question": "erw\u00e4hnen", "answer": "to mention", "options": ["to drop in", "to keep, to hold", "to mention", "to stick"]}, {"numb": 49, "question": "auftreten", "answer": "to occur, \u0c95\u0cbe\u0ca3\u0cbf\u0cb8\u0cbf\u0c95\u0ccaLLu", "options": ["to keep, to hold", "to miss something \u0ca4\u0caa\u0ccd\u0caa\u0cc1\u0cb5\u0cbf\u0c95\u0cc6", "to occur, \u0c95\u0cbe\u0ca3\u0cbf\u0cb8\u0cbf\u0c95\u0ccaLLu", "to exhibit, to show"]}, {"numb": 50, "question": "sich_verhalten", "answer": "to behave", "options": ["to behave", "to enter", "to connect", "to voice, \u0ca7\u0ccd\u0cb5\u0ca8\u0cbf \u0c8e\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0ca4\u0cc1"]}, {"numb": 51, "question": "ausstellen", "answer": "to exhibit, to show", "options": ["to watch", "to feed", "to exhibit, to show", "to be glad"]}, {"numb": 52, "question": "wachsen", "answer": "to grow", "options": ["to host, to arrange, event \u0c86\u0caf\u0cc6\u0cc2\u0cd5\u0c9c\u0cbf\u0cb8u", "to correspond", "to grow", "to permitted, to allower"]}, {"numb": 53, "question": "Strecken", "answer": "to stretch, to spread out", "options": ["to spread, \u0cb9\u0cb0\u0ca1u", "to stretch, to spread out", "to feed", "to fill in"]}, {"numb": 54, "question": "sch\u00e4digen", "answer": "to harm, to injure", "options": ["to harm, to injure", "to pass, to go through", "to byepass", "to settle"]}, {"numb": 55, "question": "auffallen", "answer": "attract attention, to stand out", "options": ["to keep up, to match up", "to fill in", "attract attention, to stand out", "to keep, to hold"]}, {"numb": 56, "question": "stecken", "answer": "to stick", "options": ["to ensure", "to watch", "to stick", "to get nervous"]}, {"numb": 57, "question": "messen", "answer": "to measure", "options": ["to betray", "to measure", "well being", "to relax"]}, {"numb": 58, "question": "verbunden", "answer": "to connect", "options": ["to connect", "to close, to shut", "attract attention, to stand out", "to spread, \u0cb9\u0cb0\u0ca1u"]}, {"numb": 59, "question": "beantragen", "answer": "to reqest, to apply for", "options": ["to reqest, to apply for", "to pull", "discourage, \u0ca8\u0cbf\u0cb0\u0cc1\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0cb8\u0cbe\u0cb9\u0c97\u0cca\u0cb3\u0cbfsu", "to confirm, to approve"]}, {"numb": 60, "question": "abl\u00e4ufen", "answer": "to expire", "options": ["to behave", "to close, to shut", "to expire", "to make trip"]}, {"numb": 61, "question": "\u00fcberlegen", "answer": "to consider", "options": ["to close, to shut", "to exist", "to stick", "to consider"]}, {"numb": 62, "question": "entstehen", "answer": "to arise, to emerge, \u0cb9\u0cca\u0cb0\u0cb9\u0cca\u0cae\u0ccd\u0cae\u0cc1, \u0c89\u0ca6\u0ccd\u0cad\u0cb5\u0cbf\u0cb8u", "options": ["to pack something", "to arise, to emerge, \u0cb9\u0cca\u0cb0\u0cb9\u0cca\u0cae\u0ccd\u0cae\u0cc1, \u0c89\u0ca6\u0ccd\u0cad\u0cb5\u0cbf\u0cb8u", "to suit", "to mark"]}, {"numb": 63, "question": "eignen_sich", "answer": "to suit", "options": ["to suit", "to put on it", "to decide", "to restrict"]}, {"numb": 64, "question": "mithalten", "answer": "to keep up, to match up", "options": ["to restrain, \u0ca8\u0cbf\u0caf\u0c82\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0cb0\u0ca3 maadikoLLu", "to keep up, to match up", "to swap", "to occur, \u0c95\u0cbe\u0ca3\u0cbf\u0cb8\u0cbf\u0c95\u0ccaLLu"]}, {"numb": 65, "question": "erledigen", "answer": "to settle", "options": ["to fill up (bitta sthala tumbi)", "to settle", "to exhibit, to show", "to consider"]}, {"numb": 66, "question": "feststehen", "answer": "to be fixe", "options": ["to be fixe", "to arise, to emerge, \u0cb9\u0cca\u0cb0\u0cb9\u0cca\u0cae\u0ccd\u0cae\u0cc1, \u0c89\u0ca6\u0ccd\u0cad\u0cb5\u0cbf\u0cb8u", "to surround", "to critisize"]}, {"numb": 67, "question": "halten", "answer": "to keep, to hold", "options": ["to prefer", "to quit", "to keep, to hold", "to be located"]}, {"numb": 68, "question": "eingehen", "answer": "to enter", "options": ["to link", "to invent", "to mention", "to enter"]}, {"numb": 69, "question": "kritisieren", "answer": "to critisize", "options": ["to mention", "to be fixe", "to critisize", "to recommond"]}, {"numb": 70, "question": "wohlbefinden", "answer": "well being", "options": ["well being", "to drop in", "to betray", "to insert"]}, {"numb": 71, "question": "erfinden", "answer": "to invent", "options": ["to occur, \u0c95\u0cbe\u0ca3\u0cbf\u0cb8\u0cbf\u0c95\u0ccaLLu", "to invent", "to surround", "to host, to arrange, event \u0c86\u0caf\u0cc6\u0cc2\u0cd5\u0c9c\u0cbf\u0cb8u"]}, {"numb": 72, "question": "tauschen", "answer": "to swap", "options": ["to restrict", "to applz for job", "to swap", "to train"]}, {"numb": 73, "question": "stimmen", "answer": "to voice, \u0ca7\u0ccd\u0cb5\u0ca8\u0cbf \u0c8e\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0ca4\u0cc1", "options": ["to keep, to hold", "to voice, \u0ca7\u0ccd\u0cb5\u0ca8\u0cbf \u0c8e\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0ca4\u0cc1", "to grow", "to pass, to go through"]}, {"numb": 74, "question": "verlinken", "answer": "to link", "options": ["to applz for job", "to drop in", "to prove", "to link"]}, {"numb": 75, "question": "betreffen", "answer": "to affect, \u0caa\u0cb0\u0cbf\u0ca3\u0cbe\u0cae\u0cb5\u0cbe\u0c97\u0cc1", "options": ["to affect, \u0caa\u0cb0\u0cbf\u0ca3\u0cbe\u0cae\u0cb5\u0cbe\u0c97\u0cc1", "to reqest, to apply for", "to receive", "to look at"]}, {"numb": 76, "question": "umstellen", "answer": "to shift", "options": ["to get nervous", "to suffer", "to shift", "to voice, \u0ca7\u0ccd\u0cb5\u0ca8\u0cbf \u0c8e\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0ca4\u0cc1"]}, {"numb": 77, "question": "existeren", "answer": "to exist", "options": ["to exist", "to train", "to fill up (bitta sthala tumbi)", "to lose"]}, {"numb": 78, "question": "ern\u00e4hren", "answer": "to feed", "options": ["to feed", "to host, to arrange, event \u0c86\u0caf\u0cc6\u0cc2\u0cd5\u0c9c\u0cbf\u0cb8u", "to be fixe", "to shift"]}, {"numb": 79, "question": "zogen", "answer": "to pull", "options": ["to keep, to hold", "to permitted, to allower", "to install", "to pull"]}, {"numb": 80, "question": "statten", "answer": "to permitted, to allower", "options": ["to insert", "to decide", "to permitted, to allower", "to feed"]}, {"numb": 81, "question": "einbauen", "answer": "to install", "options": ["to applz for job", "to be located", "to defend", "to install"]}, {"numb": 82, "question": "zur\u00fcckhalten", "answer": "to restrain, \u0ca8\u0cbf\u0caf\u0c82\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0cb0\u0ca3 maadikoLLu", "options": ["to confirm, to approve", "to leave", "to restrain, \u0ca8\u0cbf\u0caf\u0c82\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0cb0\u0ca3 maadikoLLu", "to relax"]}, {"numb": 83, "question": "angucken", "answer": "to look at", "options": ["to look at", "encourage, \u0caa\u0ccd\u0cb0\u0cc6\u0cc2\u0cd5\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0cb8\u0cbe\u0cb9\u0cbf\u0cb8", "superstitious, andhavishwasa", "to measure"]}, {"numb": 84, "question": "drankommen", "answer": "to have ones turn", "options": ["to defend", "to have ones turn", "to make contact", "to look at"]}, {"numb": 85, "question": "\u00fcberzeugen", "answer": "to convience, \u0cae\u0ca8\u0cb5\u0cc6\u0cc2\u0cb2\u0cbf\u0cb8u, \u0cae\u0ca8\u0c97\u0cbe\u0ca3\u0cbf\u0cb8\u0cc1", "options": ["to restrain, \u0ca8\u0cbf\u0caf\u0c82\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0cb0\u0ca3 maadikoLLu", "to surround", "to make trip", "to convience, \u0cae\u0ca8\u0cb5\u0cc6\u0cc2\u0cb2\u0cbf\u0cb8u, \u0cae\u0ca8\u0c97\u0cbe\u0ca3\u0cbf\u0cb8\u0cc1"]}, {"numb": 86, "question": "liegen", "answer": "to be located", "options": ["to settle", "to audition", "to be located", "to exhibit, to show"]}, {"numb": 87, "question": "auff\u00fcllen", "answer": "to fill in", "options": ["to bear, to abide", "to suit", "to fill in", "to be located"]}, {"numb": 88, "question": "umgeben", "answer": "to surround", "options": ["to feed", "to betray", "to surround", "to applz for job"]}, {"numb": 89, "question": "entmutigen", "answer": "discourage, \u0ca8\u0cbf\u0cb0\u0cc1\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0cb8\u0cbe\u0cb9\u0c97\u0cca\u0cb3\u0cbfsu", "options": ["discourage, \u0ca8\u0cbf\u0cb0\u0cc1\u0ca4\u0ccd\u0cb8\u0cbe\u0cb9\u0c97\u0cca\u0cb3\u0cbfsu", "to pull", "to confirm, to approve", "to consider"]}, {"numb": 90, "question": "bewerben_sich", "answer": "to applz for job", "options": ["to applz for job", "to quit", "to consider", "to critisize"]}, {"numb": 91, "question": "befinden", "answer": "to decide", "options": ["to decide", "to pass, to go through", "to make contact", "to restrict"]}, {"numb": 92, "question": "gelten", "answer": "to take effect, \u0c9c\u0cbe\u0cb0\u0cbf\u0caf\u0cb2\u0ccd\u0cb2\u0cbf\u0cb0\u0cbfvudu (rule, law)", "options": ["to affect, \u0caa\u0cb0\u0cbf\u0ca3\u0cbe\u0cae\u0cb5\u0cbe\u0c97\u0cc1", "to take effect, \u0c9c\u0cbe\u0cb0\u0cbf\u0caf\u0cb2\u0ccd\u0cb2\u0cbf\u0cb0\u0cbfvudu (rule, law)", "to make contact", "to train"]}, {"numb": 93, "question": "erg\u00e4nzen", "answer": "to fill up (bitta sthala tumbi)", "options": ["to keep, to hold", "to fill up (bitta sthala tumbi)", "to lose", "to suit"]}, {"numb": 94, "question": "ausbreiten", "answer": "to spread, \u0cb9\u0cb0\u0ca1u", "options": ["to suffer, to endure", "to consider", "to spend time", "to spread, \u0cb9\u0cb0\u0ca1u"]}, {"numb": 95, "question": "verbringen", "answer": "to spend time", "options": ["to keep, to hold", "to expire", "to spend time", "to miss something \u0ca4\u0caa\u0ccd\u0caa\u0cc1\u0cb5\u0cbf\u0c95\u0cc6"]}, {"numb": 96, "question": "best\u00e4tigen", "answer": "to confirm, to approve", "options": ["to suffer, to endure", "to confirm, to approve", "to mark", "to bear, to abide"]}, {"numb": 97, "question": "geschlo\u00dfen", "answer": "to close, to shut", "options": ["to convience, \u0cae\u0ca8\u0cb5\u0cc6\u0cc2\u0cb2\u0cbf\u0cb8u, \u0cae\u0ca8\u0c97\u0cbe\u0ca3\u0cbf\u0cb8\u0cc1", "to close, to shut", "to fill up (bitta sthala tumbi)", "to pass, to go through"]}, {"numb": 98, "question": "speichern", "answer": "to save data", "options": ["to look at", "to shift", "to save data", "to grow"]}, {"numb": 99, "question": "verloren", "answer": "to lose", "options": ["to affect, \u0caa\u0cb0\u0cbf\u0ca3\u0cbe\u0cae\u0cb5\u0cbe\u0c97\u0cc1", "to quit", "to stretch, to spread out", "to lose"]}];